A multitasker is one who can perform two or more tasks effectively at the same time, which—apart from the obvious differences—is similar to what a computer does.
多任务处理者是指能够同时有效完成两项或更多任务的人；撇开明显的差异不谈，这与计算机所做的事相似。
The concept does indeed come from the realms of technology, where it is used to refer to an operating system that can execute multiple tasks at the same time.
这一概念确实源自技术领域，在技术领域中用来指能够同时执行多项任务的操作系统。
However, the question is: can a person really be a multitasker?
然而，问题是：人真的能成为多任务处理者吗？
For most scientists, the answer is no.
在大多数科学家看来，答案是否定的。
Indeed, according to experts in neuroscience, our brains do not handle multitasking situations well.
的确，据神经科学专家说，我们的大脑并不能很好地应对多任务处理的情况。
As soon as two tasks require our attention, productivity suffers.
一旦有两项任务需要我们关注，工作效率就会下降。
What we call multitasking, therefore, is in reality the ability to move more or less quickly from one task to another.
因此，我们所说的多任务处理，实际上是或快或慢地从一项任务转到另一项任务的能力。
This requires two essential conditions: that one of the tasks needs to be automatic, like walking or eating, and that they both need different mental processes.
这需要具备两个必要条件：一是其中一项任务必须是自动进行的，比如走路或吃饭；二是两项任务需要不同的心理过程。
Answering the phone and writing at the same time, for example.
例如，同时接电话和写东西。
However, on the other side of the coin there are people who maintain that it is possible to be, or at least seem to be, multitasking.
然而，从另一面来看，也有人坚持认为，人有可能做到多任务处理，或者至少看起来是在多任务处理。
A recent study concluded that regardless of whether people are actually handling several tasks or not, the mere fact that they perceive this activity as multitasking has a positive effect on their performance.
最近一项研究得出结论：无论人们实际上是否在处理几项任务，单是他们把这种活动视为多任务处理这一事实，就会对其表现产生积极影响。
The business perspective offers a different view: multitasking is understood as the ability to adapt to all types of environment within a company and effectively undertake different activities within a set time frame.
商业视角给出了不同的看法：多任务处理被理解为一种能力，即能适应公司内部的各类环境，并在规定时限内有效地从事不同的活动。
Indeed, many companies look for people who are skilled in multitasking to improve their productivity.
的确，许多公司都在寻找擅长多任务处理的人，以提高工作效率。
From this different perspective, not only can you be multitasking, but this ability can also be taught: something that is easier in fluid organisations, which favour flexibility in their working practices.
从这一不同的视角来看，人不仅能够多任务处理，而且这种能力还可以传授：这在灵活多变的组织中更容易做到，这类组织在工作方式上青睐灵活性。
The benefits of multitasking are clear.
多任务处理的好处显而易见。
Being quicker and more efficient increases our performance and the number of tasks completed.
做事更快、效率更高，会提升我们的表现，并增加完成的任务数量。
But having to pay attention to several things at once means that the powers of concentration are reduced, and that can lead to more mistakes.
但必须同时关注几件事，意味着专注力会降低，而这可能导致更多错误。